American Marketing Association, New York Capital Region Chapter; Records apap207
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
American Marketing Association, New York Capital Region Records
1992-2013
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
American Marketing Association, New York Capital Region
apap207
2.81 cubic ft.
The American Marketing Association, Capital District Chapter works for the advancement of business and management in the region. The collection includes publications concerning programs sponsored by the organization as well as administrative records. Also included are descriptions and handouts from businesses in the Capital District.
Collection X
Scope and Contents
The American Marketing Association, Capital District Records mainly consists of administrative records, such as board agendas, minutes, chapter plans, surveys and financial documents. In additon, there are Mark of Excellence Awards materials and copies of the organization's publication Positions & Perceptions. Also, there is a box of compact discs, cassette tapes and floppy disks.
Arrangement
Records were arranged chronologically. Smaller editions of the newsletter, Positions & Perceptions, were interfiled while larger editions were separated into an oversized box. Two large binders were taken apart but original order was retained.
Biographical / Historical
The American Marketing Association (AMA) was founded in 1937. Today the AMA has expanded greatly and is one of the largest marketing organizations in the world. It has over 30,000 members across the world who are knowledgeable in the marketing field. The American Marketing Association, New York State Captial Region chapter was formed in 1993 after holding general interest and planning meetings throughout 1992. Its first president was University at Albany, SUNY associate professor, Paul Schurr.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives from the New York Capital Region Chapter of the American Marketing Association in 2010 January and 2016 March.
Minutes (administrative records); American Marketing Association, New York Capital Region Chapter; Marketing; Associations, institutions, etc.--New York (State)--Albany; Awards; American Marketing Association
- AMA Interest Group - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Meeting Notes, 1992-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- AMA Interest Group - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Meeting Notes, 1992-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cassettes, Floppy Disks and CD Roms, 1992-2007; Undated (Artifact-box 1)
- Positions & Perceptions, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "Amalgamation", 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Chapter Formation and Officer Election Ballots, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Board of Directors Meetings (1 of 2), 1993-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Board of Directors Meetings (2 of 2), 1993-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Positions & Perceptions, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Nominations + Membership Directories, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Strategic Planning - Chapter Plan, 1994-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Secretary/ Board Meeting, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Chapter Plan, 1995; 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Entry For 1994-1995 Chapter of Excellence Awards Program (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Positions & Perceptions, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Treasurer, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Board of Directors '97-'98, 1995; 1997-1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 1999-2000 Board of Directors, 1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 2002-2003 Board of Directors (1 of 2), 1995; 2001-2003; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 2002-2003 Board of Directors (2 of 2), 1995; 2001-2003; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 2006-2007 Board Meeting, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Board Meetings, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Public Relations, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- 1995-1996 Annual Chapter Report and Administrative Records (Box 1, Folder 24)
- 1994-1995 Chapter Excellence Award, 1995-1996; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Positions & Perceptions, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- 1996-1997 Chapter Plan (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Mark of Excellence Awards, 1996; 1998-2003 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Board Meetings, 1996-1997; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Positions & Perceptions, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Collegiate Relations, 1997; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Marketing Student Summit, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Positions & Perceptions, 1997-2010 (Oversized 1)
- 1998-1999 Chapter Plan (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 1997-98 Chapter Excellence Award Entry (1 of 2 ), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 1997-98 Chapter Excellence Award Entry (2 of 2 ), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Member Survey, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Steering Committee, 1998-1999; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1998-1999 Board of Directors, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Non- Member Survey, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 2000-2001 Board of Directors, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Interment Symposium, 2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 2001-2002 Board of Directors, 2000-2002; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Technology Symposium, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Member Survey, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 2003-2004 Board of Directors, 2002-2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Marketing Materials, 2002-2008; 2010-2012; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Mark of Excellence Program Evaluation, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Technology Symposium, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 2004-2005 Board of Directors (1 of 2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- 2004-2005 Board of Directors (1 of 2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- 2005-2006 Board of Directors, 2004-2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Mark of Excellence Awards, 2004-2010 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Finance Committee/ Budget, 2005-2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
- 2005 Member/ Non- Member Survey, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- 2006-2007 Chapter Plan (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 2007-2008 Board of Directors (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 2007-2008 Board of Directors and Finance Committee, 2007-2009; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 2008-2009 Board of Directors and Roundtable Survey Report (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Finance Committee/ Budget, 2009-2011; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Member/ Non-Member Survey, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Positions & Perceptions, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Positions & Perceptions, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Mark of Excellence Awards, 2011-2013 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Positions & Perceptions, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Sample of Membership Application, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)